cruisecheap.com 2012-06-17

# Privacy Policy

Protecting your privacy is important to us. This privacy statement covers CruiseCheap.com and all the websites of WMPH Incorporated (hereinafter referred to as "WMPH"). We hope the following statement will help you understand how WMPH collects, uses, and safeguards the personal information you provide us on our site. 

  * What personally identifiable information WMPH collects. 
  * What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site 
  * What organization collects the information 
  * How WMPH uses the information 
  * With whom WMPH may share user information 
  * What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 
  * What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under WMPH control. 
  * How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should contact us at [support@cruisecheap.com](mailto:support@cruisecheap.com)

## **Information Collection and Use**

**Information Collection**

WMPH is the sole owner of the information collected on our website. WMPH collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site. 

**Reservation**  
We request information from the user on our Cruise Request Form and Group Request Form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date) if a reservation is made online. This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer’s reservations. If we have trouble processing a reservation, the information is used to contact the user. 

## **Information Use**

**Profile**  
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user’s visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do not share your profile with other third parties, however, on occasion we may direct market products to you on behalf of our business partners.. Your profile is shared in aggregate form only. 

**Cookies  
**A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use [both] session ID cookies [and] persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. 

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**  
Our third party advertising companies does not employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. [Clear gifs are tied to users’ personally identifiable information.] [Clear gifs are not tied to users’ personally identifiable information.] 

Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited “www.companyX.com”, which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the Web site [or advertising company] would match the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be given to the advertising company [or Web site]. 

We do use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the Opt-out section. 

## **Communications from the Site**

**Special Offers and Updates**  
We will send all new members a welcoming. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. 

**Newsletter**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. 

**Service Announcements**  
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. [Users may opt-out of these communications. Please see our Choice and Opt-out section.] 

**Customer Service**  
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes. 

## **Sharing**

**Legal Disclaimer**  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site. 

**Business Transitions**  
In the event WMPH goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

**Choice/Opt-out**  
Our users are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. For example, our order form has an ‘opt-out’ mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don’t want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at unsubscribe@CruiseCheap.com 

**Links**  
This Web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

**Chat Rooms, Message Boards, and Public Forums**  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, by posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

**Security**  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our reservation form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our booking form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’. 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment with our Internet Service Provider. 

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done by emailing our Customer Support at support@cruisecheap.com. [Or, contact us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below]. 

**Notification of Changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users [via email] and by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days/ 

**Contact Information**

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

  * WMPH Vacations / CruiseCheap.com  
220 Congress Park Drive  
Suite 140  
Delray Beach, Florida 33445  
Phone: 561-243-2100  
Fax: 561-243-0007  

**For Cruise Reservations, please call: Toll Free: 1-800-439-1909**

**WMPH Vacations  
**_Building personal and lasting relationships by consistently exceeding expectations.™_
